# DMYTRO AFANASIEV

#### FRONTEND DEVELOPER

#### **CONTACTS**:

Calgary, Alberta, Canada | +15879699718 | dimaafanasiev3@gmail.coм

#### **SUMMARY:**

Frontend Developer with over 5 years of experience in React.js, Vue.js, Typescript and Tailwind. Currently based in Calgary. Delivered 30+ web projects on time. Demonstrated ability in leading teams to increase efficiency and manage projects effectively. Passionately committed to continuous learning and staying current with evolving industry trends and technologies.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

FRONTEND DEVELOPER oXyShop, Brno, Czech Republic August 2022 - May 2023

- Brought to life 20+ new features for e-shops using Vue.js, Nuxt.js, TypeScript and Tailwind
- Applied effective communication skills to collaborate with the backend development team to integrate frontend and backend functionality
- Improved overall UI and troubleshoot issues during development in Agile environment
- Performed code reviews and implemented best practices, resulting improvement in code quality and maintainability
- Implemented Cypress for testing, reducing the number of post-deployment issues.

**TEAM LEAD FRONTEND DEVELOPER** Bold Identities, UK, Remote May 2021 - July 2022

- Managed a development team of 5, ensuring projects were delivered in a timely and efficient manner using leadership skills
- Collaborated with clients to meet their needs, always paying close attention to detail and easily adapting to changes
- Utilized HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, and Next.js to develop high-quality, userfriendly websites
- Performed code reviews and utilized modern managing practices in Agile environment resulting increased team efficiency by 30%

FRONTEND DEVELOPER Bold Identities, UK, Remote May 2018 - April 2021

- Applied HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, along with React.js and Next.js, in the development of UI for high-quality web applications.
- Executed 30+ design mockups, maintained frontend features, and collaborated with team to meet or exceed deadlines
- Developed a new component library that development time by 25% and integrated frontend and backend functionality using innovation and computer programming skills

# **EDUCATION**:

# BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE: INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Brno University of Technology - Brno, Czech Republic September 2021 - Current

JUNIOR SPECIALIST: INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Kharkiv Radio Engineering College - Kharkiv, Ukraine September 2017 - June 2021

# TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- Frontend: HTML5, CSS (Tailwind, Bootstrap, SASS), JavaScript (React.js, Next.js, React Native, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Blazor), TypeScript
- State Management: Redux, Vuex, Pinia
- Backend: Node.js, PHP, Twig
- Database: MySQL, MongoDB
- Cloud Services: Firebase, Azure, AWS
- Module bundlers: Webpack, Rollup.js
- Testing: Cypress, Jest
- Containerization Tools: Docker, Docker Compose
- APIs: REST, GraphQL
- Package managers: npm, yarn, pnpm
- Design Tools: Figma, Adobe XD
  IDEs: PhpStorm Visual Studio C
- IDEs: PhpStorm, Visual Studio CodeOperating Systems: Windows, Linux
- Version Control: GIT (GitHub and GitLab)
- Project Management: Agile, Scrum, Jira

# LANGUAGES:

- English (B2)
- · Czech (B2)
- Ukrainian (Native)
- Russian (Native)

# LINKS:

HTTPS://WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/DMYTRO-AFANASIEV-216574219/

HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/DMYTROVOLODYMYRSON